在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime...
找到最后四个铁堡遗物是我们的当务之急
It is paramount that we recover the final four Iacon relics...
它们是“终极之钥”
the Omega keys.
钥匙？
Keys?
能打开什么？
To what?
我们的故乡涅重生的关键…
The regeneration of our home planet.
一座古墓？
A tomb.
据说这座古墓里长眠着一位元祖领袖！
One known to contain the remains of Primes.
终于 领袖的力量现在属于我了！
At long last, the power of the Primes belongs to me!
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四组加密坐标
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
这是我的第一件作品
My first creation
以宇宙大帝之血铸就
fashioned from the very blood of Unicron.
我称之为暗黑星辰剑
I call it the Dark Star Saber.
快点 交出遗物
The relic. now!
哦 你是说这个？谁找到归谁！
Oh, you mean this? Finders keepers.
你该看看擎天柱当时的表情！
You should have seen Optimus Prime's face
当他的宝贝星辰剑连同他的美梦\N和汽车人的胜利一起如玻璃般破碎之时
when his precious Star Saber shattered like glass and, with it his dreams of an Autobot victory.
毫无疑问
Granted
擎天柱抢占剩余遗物的决心会更加坚决
Optimus will be more determined than ever to discover
啊 很好
Ah, very good.
看来你已破译出了下一个坐标
I see you have decoded the next set of coordinates.
真有你的 声波
Way to step things up, Soundwave.
我真希望这回别又是什么神圣之物
I do hope this Iacon relic is something less sacred and more profane
最好是电磁毁灭炮之类的
like an electro-disruptor cannon.
那会更加实用
We could use one of those.
说的不错 击倒
Indeed, Knockout.
骇翼 立刻向舰桥报告！
Dreadwing, report to the bridge immediately.
我恳求您 威震天陛下
Please, lord Megatron
将找回遗物的荣耀赐予属下
allow me the honor of retrieving this relic for you.
我很惊讶 那次“事故”之后 你这么快就无所畏惧了么？
I'm surprised you would risk your finish so soon after your accident.
尽管如此 我还是反复劝说自己 你是这次任务的最佳人选
Nonetheless, I remain unconvinced that you are the best choice for the task
虽然你没能拿回相位仪
since you failed to secure the phase shifter.
那是因为我缺乏合适的工具
I lacked the proper tools.
既然声波现在抽不出身
But since Soundwave's currently occupied
我想您不会介意我借用一下这个
I can't imagine he'll mind if I borrow this...
用它来带回您的战利品
So that I might better secure your prize
同时狠狠地教训那些汽车人！
and heap some hurt on the Autobots.
总有一天 我要成为像擎天柱那样伟大的战士
I'm gonna be a great warrior someday, like Optimus.
没错…好好学习 天天向上
Well, train hard and gain some wisdom along the way
你一定能如愿以偿的
and I'm sure it'll happen.
哦 那当然 这可是我的宿命
Oh, it will. It's my destiny.
何以见得？
How so?
你看 一分钟前我还在铁堡当保安
Well, one minute I'm on security detail at Iacon.
下一分钟我醒来 就到了银河系的另一边
The next, I wake up on the other side of the galaxy
成为了擎天柱的部下
to find myself under Optimus' command.
我是说 这种事可不常见吧？
I mean, what are the chances, right?
这…这一定事出有因
Things happen for a reason.
我们懂了 烟幕
We get it, Smokescreen.
你是特别的 有你在是我们的造化
You're special. We're lucky to have you.
我真正想说的只是…
All I'm really saying is
我跋山涉水来到这里 可不想辜负了这个机会
I've come a long way, and this is one opportunity I don't plan on messing up.
汽车人 下一个铁堡遗物的坐标已经破解
Autobots, the next Iacon coordinates have been decoded.
救护车 准备好环陆桥
Ratchet, ready the ground bridge.
最后一个摸到终极之钥的 倒一个礼拜能量废罐！
Last one to the Omega key has to scrub the Energon tanks for a week.
我们还计分呢？
Didn't know we were keeping score.
阿尔茜 大黄蜂 准备出发！
Arcee, Bumblebee, prepare to roll out.
等等！那我呢？
Wait. What about me?
哼
Hum.
我是说 我和隔板呢？
I mean me and Bulkhead.
你们二人在此待命
The two of you will remain here
以防我在他们回来之前就破译出下一个坐标
in the event i'm able to decode a subsequent database entry before the others return.
擎天柱是对的 考虑到塞博特恩的命运危在旦夕
Optimus is right. Considering the very fate of Cybertron is at stake
反应时间就至关重要
response time is critical.
敬候佳音吧 小子
Keep your engines idling, kid.
走吧 小蜂“宿命”在等着我们呢
Come on, Bee. Destiny awaits.
这叫中场休息
We call it a pit stop.
咱们会回到赛场的
We'll get back in the race.
在那儿
Over there.
看谁来了 正是人家所期待的呢
Well, well, just the Autobots I wanted to see.
我来对付变态医生 你去抢钥匙
I'll handle the mad doctor. You grab the key.
人家正想为过往的回忆…感谢你们呢！
I've been waiting to thank you both for all the memories.
谁能想到“声波”也有如此魅力…能“击倒”众生！
Who knew that sound waves could be such a.... Knockout?
脚步声太慌张了 我都能听到！
What's that, dear? I can't hear you!
小蜂 快抢遗物！
Bee, the relic!
讨厌！
Scrap.
这东西…也能这么用
How low can it go?
要么放手要么去死
Subwoofer or depth charge?
糟了！
Scrap.
嗯…这个和擎天柱从我手中抢走的一模一样
It appears identical to the one taken from me by Optimus Prime.
或许这是汽车人故意让你抢走的赝品
Ah. Perhaps it is a decoy the Autobots allowed you to seize
好妨碍我们的行动？
as a means of sabotage.
看起来不像 我的君王
Unlikely, my liege.
他们为夺此物简直是奋不顾身
They battled too desperately for it.
或许 这只是整盘棋局里的一小步？
Then pieces of a larger puzzle, perhaps.
做得好 声波
Excellent, Soundwave.
运气好的话 这些新坐标会为我们理清头绪
Coordinates will shed some light on the subject.
声波真是锋头正劲啊 我也一样！
Soundwave's on fire. And so I am.
别被虚荣冲昏了头脑 医生
Keep your vanity in check, doctor.
难道我还没证明自己吗？
Haven't I proven myself?!
对我而言 你更大的价值在于使用专业的科学技能
Your scientific expertise remains of greater use to me
来分析我们新的战利品
analyzing our latest acquisition.
我必须知道这是何物 有何用途
I must know what this relic is and what it can do.
对不起 擎天柱
I'm sorry, Optimus.
击倒早就等在那里了
Knockout was there, waiting for us.
看来虎子们的破译水平提高了
Seems the 'Cons are improving their decoding skills.
鉴于两块终极之钥已经分开
And it seems that, with two keys already separated
眼下无人能让塞博特恩重现生机了
no one currently possesses the means to revive Cybertron.
尽管我们复兴故乡的工作陷入了僵局
While our quest to restore our planet may have reached a stalemate
保护好已有的终极之钥仍是当务之急
securing the remaining keys is still the most prudent course of action.
天啊 击倒还有那声波武器什么的一定很刺激！
Man, it must have been crazy with Knockout going all sonic.
我真希望当时也在场 好…
Oh, I wish I'd been there. I would have...
好什么？
Would have what?
好像上一次一样夺回钥匙？
Recovered the key like you did the first one?
或许吧 谁知道呢？
Maybe. Who knows?
我只是想把所见之物都轰成渣
I just want us to be firing on all cylinders
你知道 我们已经失去了星辰剑
you know, now that the Star Saber's gone.
而我目前为止干得还不错
And I have a pretty good track record so far.
听着 小子 阿尔茜和大黄蜂并没有气馁
Look, kid, Arcee and Bumblebee are no slouches
在没有那把大剑的漫长岁月中 擎天柱也一直做得很好
and Optimus managed just fine for eons without the big sword.
当然 你不可能知道这些
Of course, you wouldn't know about that.
当我们在此奋战之时 你还在外太空飘着呢！
And you've been locked in stasis the whole time we've been fighting this war.
所以！我已准备好弥补错失的时间了！
Exactly, and I'm ready to make up for lost time.
那得等擎天柱说你行才可以
When Optimus says you're ready.
你要耐心等待
You got to be in this for the long haul.
稳扎稳打才能赢得比赛
Slow and steady wins the race.
啊…怎么还没好！
Hurry up, already!
提速能量怎么会比普通能量液化得更慢？！
How is it possible that speed-enhancing Energon takes longer to process than regular Energon?!
整整一大块红色能量才液化成这么一丁点儿？
An entire chunk of Red Energon, and this is all I get?!
这顶多够我喝一口…最多两口！
There's enough here for one dose, maybe two!
霸天虎有动作了？
Mmm. Decepticon movement.
超级速度或许代替不了精锐护甲的强大威力
While speed is hardly a suitable replacement for the might of the Apex armor
不过 却能让我在抢夺强大的先祖遗物时占尽先机
it should provide me with enough of an edge to obtain a more formidable relic.
下一个坐标破译了！
The next coordinates are ready.
那么只剩最后一个了
There remains one set left to decode.
马上就去 老大
On it, boss.
我一定会把钥匙带回来
I'm gonna bring back that key.
嗯…小隔
Uh, Bulk?
是不是落下什么了？
Forgetting something?
看好咱们的“宿命之子” 好吗？
Make sure you keep an eye on destiny's child, okay?
哈…跟照顾神子比起来 简直小菜一碟
Compared to watching Miko, piece of cake.
靠近点 提高警惕
Stick close. And stay focused.
我懂
Gotcha!
我是认真的！
I mean it.
我也是！
Me too.
那是什么声音？
What is that?
是你丧钟的鸣响！
One of the last sounds that you will ever hear.
骇翼…
Dreadwing.
我们得马上离开这儿 快！
We got to get out of here, now!
烟仔 我来对付骇翼 你快去拿遗物！
Smoke, I'll handle Dreadwing. Go get the relic.
没问题！
You got it.
你就喜欢躲在暗处放冷箭 对吧？
You love doing your dirty work from a distance, don't you?
真可惜 你没种跟我堂堂正正地较量一番！
Too bad you don't have the ball bearings to fight up close and personal.
就目前的情况而言
In this particular case
我很乐意为你破例！
I will be all too happy to make an exception.
你的努力值得夸奖
An admirable effort
但你显然忘了咱们上次的交手是如何收场的
but you obviously forgot how our last encounter ended.
不 我没忘
No, I didn't.
烟仔 我马上就来
Smoke, I'm on my way.
我的宿命…
Destiny.
烟幕！醒醒！
Smokescreen! Wake up!
呃…发生什么事了？
Wh-what happened?
我还想问你呢
That's what I want to know.
终极之钥！
The Omega key.
我都拿到了！
I had it
直到什么东西从背后袭击了我…
until something hit me from behind.
骇翼肯定有帮手
Dreadwing must have had backup.
那个遗物早就被带走了
That relic's long gone.
救护车 打开环陆桥
Ratchet, we need a bridge.
我…我答应过擎天柱会把钥匙带回去…
I-I told Optimus I'd return with that key.
听着 孩子 钛师傅说过我们得把四个钥匙都弄到手
Listen, kid, Alpha Trion said we need all four keys
才能让塞博特恩重生 记得吗？
to restore Cybertron, remember?
我们只要保护好手头上的
We just need to hang on to the one we have
再想法从威震天那里把剩下的抢过来就行了
and find a way to get the others back from Megatron.
塞博特恩重生的希望…掌握在我的手上
The promise of a new Cybertron in the palm of my hand...
只要我能集齐全部四把钥匙！
when I obtain all four.
烟幕是被人打了闷棍
Smokescreen was sucker-punched.
换了谁都会中招的
Could have happened to any of us.
事实并非如此！
But it didn't
分明是我放下了戒心
because I was the one who dropped his guard.
是我搞砸了任务
I was the one who blew it.
我这算哪门子的“伟大”战士
Some great warrior I'm turning out to be.
你还是没搞懂 是吗？
You still don't get it, do you?
几次胜利是不足以让你成为传奇的
A couple of victories aren't gonna make you a legend.
也不是每次任务都能成功
And not every mission results in success
我不能 小蜂不能 甚至包括擎天柱在内
not for me, not for Bee, not even for Optimus.
我们得到了一些遗物 也失去了一些
We've gained relics, and we've lost some.
我们还失去过朋友 甚至失去了一个世界
We've also lost friends. We've even lost a world.
但是 这一次我们可以从头再来
But this is one time we get a do-over.
现在我们有机会让塞博特恩重生
We have a chance to bring back Cybertron
这是在场的每个人的事！
and everyone in this room needs to be in sync.
而不是你一个人的“宿命”
This isn't about you or your destiny.
阿尔茜 你说得够清楚了
Arcee, you have made your point.
擎天柱 他需要彻底明白
Optimus, he needs to hear this.
或许有一天 你真的成为了一名伟大的战士
You might actually become a great warrior one day
我真心希望如此
and I sincerely hope that you do.
但以团队为重才能造就伟大
But greatness begins and ends with putting the team first
只顾个人表现是行不通的！
not your personal scorecard.
我愿意为大家做任何事！
There's nothing I wouldn't do for you guys.
那就别总去逞英雄了
Then stop trying to be a hero
先学着当一个汽车人吧
and start being an Autobot.
你知道吗？
You know what?
或许是我还不够优秀！
Maybe I'm just not good enough.
下回擎天柱建议你打住的时候
Next time Optimus advises you to stop
你或许应该听他的
perhaps you should listen.
我去把他叫回来
I'll bring him back.
烟幕还年轻 隔板
Smokescreen is young, Bulkhead
还有很多东西要学
and has much to learn
不过现在 他需要理清一下思绪
but right now he needs to clear his thoughts.
我则需要破译最后一个铁堡坐标
And I need to finish decoding the final Iacon entry.
你竟然连遗物的影子都没瞅着？！
You never even spied the relic?!
当我到达时 它已经不见了…
By the time I reached the location, it was gone
汽车人也不见了
as were the Autobots.
优秀的忠仆不仅能抢在擎天柱之前\N破译最后一件遗物的位置
It would serve us well to not only decode the final Iacon entry before Optimus Prime does
还能抢回汽车人手中的那些！
but to recapture those relics currently held by the Autobots.
声波 把你的主要工作先放一放
Soundwave. Despite your primary task
我相信对汽车人基地的定位 你已取得进展
I trust that you have been making progress pinpointing the location of their base.
很好 根据最近得到的线索
Good. Given the recent accumulation of evidence
我们已掌握了他们的人类同伙的确切位置
we possess a clearer idea of where their human colleagues reside.
激光鸟应该很快就能抵近汽车人的藏身之处
And Laserbeak should soon determine whether the Autobots dwell in proximity.
啊 最后一组坐标也破解了
Ah. The final entry has been decoded.
你确定？
Has it?
唔…可能还有一层二级加密
Perhaps it's a layer of secondary encryption.
坐标正在形成一幅图像
The coordinates are forming an image.
为何最后的铁堡记录会如此与众不同呢？
Why would the final Iacon entry be different from the others?
没准儿这是遗物的图？
Maybe it's a picture of the relic.
不知道地点的话 光要这图能有什么用？
Of what possible use could that be to us without knowing its location?
我相信钛师傅自有原因
I trust that Alpha Trion has his reasons.
这是烟幕？！
Smokescreen?
擎天柱的新兵…
Prime's latest recruit
是最后一个铁堡遗物？
is the final relic of Iacon?
…那会是激射开的玩笑吗？
Is this that hotshot's idea of a joke?
没准儿烟幕知道钥匙在哪儿！
Maybe he knows where the key is.
…那他只是懒得说了？
And never bothered to mention it?
最可能的情况是
A more likely possibility
烟幕本身就是那个钥匙 而他自己却不知情！
is that Smokescreen himself somehow is the key, without knowing it.
无论如何 他现在的处境都极度危险！
Whatever the case, he could be in grave danger.
烟幕 立刻返回基地！
Smokescreen, return to base immediately.
他可能关掉通讯器了
He may have deactivated his comm link.
锁定他的位置 开启环陆桥！
Locate his position and prepare the ground bridge.
看来我们的次要计划 已经有回报了
It seems our side project is already paying off.
老子今天心情不好 虎子！
You picked the wrong day to mess with me, 'Con.
烟幕…
Smokescreen.
不！
No!